Guide to the James Boyd Collection of New York City Etchings 1861-1940, undated (bulk, 1910-1939) PR 7
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: New York City Etchings
  - Welsh, Devitt
    - [Old Tammany Hall, 14th Street and Fourth Avenue] (503), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 86)
    - [Old Tammany Hall, 14th Street and Fourth Avenue] (504), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 86)
  - West, Levon (1900-68)
    - Waldorf-Astoria [Fifth Avenue and 34th Street] (72), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 87)
  - Wetherill, Elisha Kent Kane (1874-1929)
    - The Gate - Gramercy Park (312), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - Old New York [First Avenue between 310-31st streets] (313), 1914 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - The Harbor [East River scene] (314), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - East Side [scene on the lower east side] (315), 1915 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - Under the Elevated [train, First Avenue near 11th St.] (316), 1924 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - Italian Grocery Shop [lower east side] (317), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - The Singer Building (412), 1924 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - The Brooklyn Bridge [Manhattan skyline] (417), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - East Side Shops [First Avenue between 6-7th streets] (418), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
    - [Looking north to Queensboro Bridge] (419), 1914 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 88)
  - Wolcott, W.
    - 42nd Street & 6th Avenue (432), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 89)
    - Lower Broadway looking north from Dey Street (352), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 89)
  - Yoshida, Hiroshi (Japanese, 1876-1950)
    - Woolworth Building (215) color woodcut, [ca. 1924] (Offsite-box 5, Folder 90)
- Oversize Prints from Series I
  - Detwiller, Frederick K. (1882-1953)
    - Pylons, Hudson River Bridge, view between 176th and 177th Sts. (508), 1928 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 91)
  - Drewes, Werner (1899-1985)
    - Central Park [looking southeast toward Fifth Avenue] (193), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 92)
    - Lower Manhattan Seen from Montague Terrace (194), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 92)
    - Wall Street (195), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 92)
  - Geissler, Paul
    - The East River (4), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 93)
    - Off for Foreign Ports [New York harbor] (5), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 93)
    - Towering Hotels at Central Park, New York (92), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 93)
    - New York Stock Exchange (94), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 93)
    - Tower of Commerce (97), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 93)
    - The Battery and West Street (356), 1929 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 93)
  - Hunter, F[rederick] Leo (1862-1943)
    - Banker's Trust Company Building looking east (239), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 94)
    - South and DePeyster Streets (242), 1879 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 94)
    - Old East India Wharf, New York (449), 1885 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 94)
  - Nankivell, Frank A.
    - Victory Arch (469), 1919 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 95)
  - Struck, Hermann
    - New York Skyline from Brooklyn (143), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 96)
  - Wallace, William H.
    - New York from Brooklyn (234), undated (Offsite-box 6, Folder 97)
    - Old Dutch Church [as Post Office] (235), 1883 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 97)
  - Monk, W.
    - Metropolitan Tower looking south from 28th St (444), undated (Box Unknown container 300 for instance of Metropolitan Tower looking south from 28th St (444), Folder 98)
      (folder is housed in oversize drawer F10)
- Series II: Accompanying Materials
  The collection also includes material from Boyd's own files: two letters (1927, 1928) from French print dealer Louis Godefroy to Boyd; New York (1927-33) and Paris (1927-31) print exhibition catalogs; four art periodicals (1899-1929); and one photograph (1933) of artist William McNulty in his studio.
  - Letters and cards to Boyd from artists and dealers, 1927-1940 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 99)
  - Paris Exhibition Catalogs, 1927-1931 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 100)
  - New York Exhibition Catalogs, 1927-1933 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 101)
  - Photographs, 1933 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 102)
  - Printed Material, 1899-1929 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 103)